Well, the administration will abide by the ruling
insofar as it affects the covered parties.
But there are also many other options
the President has to deploy federal resources
and assets under the U.S. military to Portland.
But I was making the point that under federal law,
Section Title 10 of the U.S. Code,
the President has the authority,
anytime he believes federal resources are insufficient,
to federalize the National Guard
to carry out a mission necessary for public safety.
So it's important to understand that in Portland,
ICE officers have been subjected
to over 100 nights of terrorist assault,
doxing, murder threats, violent attack,
and every other means imaginable
to try to overturn the results of the last election
through violence.
The most important point I want to make today
is that the number one and two items in the GOP platform
in 2024 were to turn back the border invasion
and carry out the largest deportation program
in American history.
Since Inauguration Day,
there's been an orchestrated campaign
of terrorism and violence against ICE officers.
Of course, we saw the recent sniper attack
against ICE officers.
They're publishing their families' photos online,
they're threatening them with murder,
they're threatening them with death,
and they're physically attacking them
in the street each and every day.
And yet, shamefully, the mayor and governor
in Portland and Oregon have refused to render aid,
leaving ICE officers to street fight every single night
against these terrorists.
You make the claim of terrorist assaults
and violence attack over 100 nights,
and yet the judge overseeing this case
says that that's untethered from reality,
and local officials on the ground
say that Trump's assertion of what's happening
is in Portland, that it's war-ravaged
and burning to the ground is far from true.
I looked at the police data,
and police have made something like 70 total arrests
since June, and there are no reports
of buildings being burned to the ground.
The White House cited a guillotine being rolled out
as a public display of rebellion,
but there isn't actually a threat
that these demonstrators are gonna overthrow the government.
Are you concerned that that response
weakens your legal argument?